hello
my name is green and welcome back to
another episode of hermitcraft as you
can see or maybe you can't see i've
actually put on the optifine shaders and
this just allows me to make everything a
bit more visible especially at night so
do let me know if you don't like it or
not but i think it does actually improve
quite a lot you can see every aspect of
the base and yep i've not actually made
much progress at all on this base since
the last time we were on but today i
really hope to do a lot of things if you
remember last episode we talked about
getting a map together to create the
weird matrix room and that is exactly
what we're going to do today a lot of
you gave me some tips on how to do it
and i think i'm going to follow them so
thank you very much to everyone that
suggested stuff and also
mumbo jumbo answered my call for
redstone help with such enthusiasm that
he made an entire video dedicated to
teaching me how to make him make a giant
elevator and i also hope to do that
today as well but i i saw that and i was
i
i'm just blushing i'm just
i'm so so happy he made me a video
it's not every day that someone makes
you a video just because you asked for
some help so this is going to be really
cool i think although i've i have
highlighted a few issues i might
actually have to get the real mumbo
jumbo and not just a video of mumbo
jumbo to help me out here i've cleared a
little space beneath and as you can see
i've kind of got ready for what i'm
going to build but
this this might work when i make it if
it doesn't i'm going to go over to
mumbo's house i'm going to be like mambo
can you help me hang the water elevator
so we're going to need an empty map
because we're going to be making that
matrix room first
but it does mean that we need to go and
find ourselves
a snowy biome
i've flown all the way to the mining
area
are there really no snow by homes
anywhere
well this is actually a blessing in
disguise because i didn't bring enough
rockets for this journey
ah being in the nether really makes a
difference look at how much you can see
compared to when the shaders are off so
this is shaders on where all of the lava
is really nice and bright and this is
with it off it still looks great it's
just a very different kind of look it
just enables you to see a lot more i
personally don't mind which one i just
prefer to be able to see as much as
possible we've replenished no
there's not is anyone getting major deja
vu here that is straight up a skeleton
horse again that's exactly where we
found jack skelobone number one
lightning does strike twice in the same
place
seriously how hard is it to find some
snow in this place i haven't found a
single snowy biome
this looks very promising but i need to
take the largest amount of space that's
going to be completely covered in white
i need to find an area that is not gonna
have any water in it cause otherwise i'm
gonna have to cover it manually this
looks very promising but i don't think
ah these rivers are gonna get in the way
maybe
so now we just take the empty map and we
get mostly mostly white oh
it has to be flat as well
i didn't account for this at all
it needs to be completely flat
because otherwise you can see the the
contour lines this isn't what i this
isn't what i expected
fortunately there's a plan b
i think this is by far going to be the
quickest way to do it
and this is actually one of the things
we need so we'll take that with us that
was a potluck
i probably would have been better off
putting some time into making an
automated pumpkin farm but now i just
gotta wait for a bunch of pumpkins i
don't need many i've only got enough
snow for well how many 13.
okay i've got all 13 pumpkins ready to
go i've got my empty maps and i think
most of you probably know what i'm going
to do i'm gonna make the snow golems do
the work for me so now all we got to do
is find a decent spot for us to do this
map it probably doesn't need to be too
far away but far enough away that we're
not in anybody's way
i have no idea if this is gonna work but
we're gonna give it a go anyway
and boop
no
ah why did i think this would work
i should have just taken one snow golem
and made sure that it works because it
definitely doesn't they don't
i mean logic dictates that these guys
don't survive in here
i really thought i could get away with
this but it doesn't look like i can
this is probably where we were before
but this is also a pretty good place to
do what we need to do looks like we're
back to square one pretty much i wonder
if it is quicker just to
make everything really flat
what have i f whose base is this
oh thank goodness i didn't do anything
here
tailing a zuma can't believe i found x i
zoom my void right here
what the heck i did not expect to see
him here
i don't even know if he's seen me yet
can i hunt yeah i got him
well my plans are definitely not going
to plan at all i need to find a place
where nobody is why is he out three
thousand blocks from spawn
this is not going well at all
okay now that we're at the back of the
base
it's time for plan c
man i really didn't think we'd get to
see because i only had a plan a
hello everyone you're probably wondering
why i'm now sitting on a chair in the
middle of the ocean and that's because i
need to sit down and take you through my
journey as you've already seen my plans
are not going particularly well and
instead of just showing you first hand
what happened
i'm going to take you through a little
story so as you know i need to make a
map that's entirely white
and that means flattening an entire area
and covering it in one block so my
initial thought was to go to a snowy
biome and then flatten it down or make a
platform
and then have it just snow that would
have been the smart way to do it but
then green thought he could be smart
which he's not
so he decided to make a few snow golems
and then harvest all of the snow all 16
000 blocks of it
now you may be wondering why on earth he
was doing this why didn't he just
flatten it it's a question that i asked
myself to this very day so i then took
that snow and i thought i would be smart
going on top of the nether and placing
all of that snow down one by one and
covering it
but i got maybe a few blocks in holding
a map and then i realized i've been
putting the square shape in the triangle
hole this entire time
i realized that
maps just don't work in the nether which
i should have known from the start
so i had 16 000 snow blocks
to do absolutely nothing with so instead
of going back to my first one instead i
decided to head to a desert where i
would flatten it down and get a lot of
sand as well
so i would kill two birds with one stone
i would have more sand than i could ever
need in the history of hermitcraft
and i would get my white map
but this meant
all of these
inexplicable mistakes
cost me 13 hours of time and that is no
exaggeration 13 hours to make this one
map and that's why this is such a messy
start to an episode if mumbo is a spoon
i am a ladle okay that covers that let's
get back into it
hopefully that all makes sense and
i finally
finally have this map
oh my goodness
there's no mistakes on it it's
completely white
ah
so this is what it looks like in the end
this giant giant landmass that's just
been flattened and got nothing on it
and now that we've got the map we need
to head back to the base
and we need to get many many copies of
this and this is also another problem
that i've come across
to make this room i'm going to need to
cover the floor the walls the roof
everything
and depending on how big the room is
that means an item frame for every
single surface and then a map for every
single item frame
now that's going to cost a lot
the first thing that we're going to need
is a lot of paper
the place to get paper is from joe
hill's
wishing well now this has been here for
ages so it says
paper for sale one stack for one good
wish
name an item with your good wish and
throw it in the well now
i need
all of this paper all of it so
in this case i'm just gonna do a few
really good wishes number one
i wish i had more paper
that seems that seems appropriate number
two
i wish i could take mumbo stash
oh it broke
uh-oh all right replace that
and the final one is
i wish for more wishes if i had the
space i would make it say this is a
genie right but
yep that'll do
[Music]
okay so i've done four wishes
i wish i had more paper
down it goes
i wish i could take mumbo's mustache in
it goes
i wish for more wishes because this is
how it works right
and i wish for one green i owe you to
joe hills for all of this paper i i
can't really do many wishes for all of
these stacks but hopefully that will
suffice for him
i'm really starting to get fond of this
base you know i was thinking as well
this like this like pattern that i've
got going on could have a gap and then
continue down in here that could look
really cool but we'll come back to that
another time i think
okay let's get this room made
so how do i copy this i've now got a
bunch of item frames
and i've got a bunch of compasses so i
can make maps
so if i take this and i put the map in
what do i need to do to turn this
into a copy
or do you need to put them in the
crafting table itself
yes
yep all the same and they stack oh
brilliant there we go we've got all of
the maps that we need
hopefully this is going to be enough oh
we're actually getting somewhere now
this shouldn't be too bad so i'm
thinking i make a meeting room down here
and that might mean making a little
funnel
so if we make a funnel down here
i just had a thought
this might be directly above the farm
that i made
oh no
[Music]
it totally is
we might need a different location for
this the pickle farm is in the way
it makes sense that the meeting room is
just here
this is the next best place i think
now all we got to do is make a little
room
the room itself needs to be made out of
sea lanterns or glowstone or something
of that sort because it needs to have a
for the effect to work the map needs to
be fully lit up so it's best if we just
make them out sea lanterns so i've
bought loads of iskall sea lanterns and
that's what we're going to make this out
of
the room itself doesn't need to be
massive
just because of the effect itself kind
of takes care of that oh my goodness
this is the big hole i have been working
on but it would be nice to have some
sort of space in here just so that you
can walk around
but any more than three blocks high and
that just creates a whole lot of issues
i'm gonna have to stop the dripping but
we're getting there and i'm definitely
gonna run out of sea lanterns
but that also indicates i'm definitely
gonna run out of maps but fortunately i
think i have enough resources to make
more i've got some paper left over
we should just about be able to make it
i haven't actually thought about how i'm
gonna get out of this room yet i'm
totally out of sea lanterns now but we
can start doing some of it to get an
idea this is the really time consuming
bit when i made this in creative mode it
took me less than five minutes because i
was able to just spam this stuff without
having to craft it at all
so
i'm really starting to take for granted
how how much i use creative mode now
and this only really works because you
can fall down this hole
and this will actually cover it up
the fact that you can place item frames
everywhere is really mad and also it's
worth noting that each one of these is
an entity so this may cause a bit of lag
i'm not entirely sure how but
it might do
and then we take the map and we put it
in each and every single one which is
why we need a lot of maps and a lot of
item frames i maybe went overboard with
the size of this room but you want to be
able to walk around and stuff i think
this is probably going to
impress mumbo or scare him but i'm
planning on having our first architect
meeting in here good old arca bros
well you definitely get an idea of how
this is gonna go
look at this it's already kind of weird
oh my this this is so strange i
absolutely love this but
i need maybe double the amount that i
have what no he's gonna break my stuff
he's breaking my maps
enough
mobs really shouldn't be spawning here
look how many glowstones there are i
think also we should make a little bit
of maybe a corridor to go around i'm
going to have to get rid of these drips
because they're that's really weird it's
like it's raining in here and i don't
really like the effect it kind of ruins
it
it turns out i'm probably not going to
have the resources to finish off the
project here so i might have to go and
do a bit of collection and then come
back to this ready for next episode
which shouldn't be too difficult but you
can see how this is going and i'm pretty
sure i can test it what is going on
how
straight up how did you get in there
why zombies don't normally just walk
into water
did he fall in
it's
possible that's so strange
i should have maybe i should have kept
him anyway
this is what it should look like if i
face well from here i could probably put
another one on the top there like an
item frame on the top and it would just
look blank but if i fall in this way
you get an idea of what this looks like
from our perspective
oh this is so and then it's ruined
because it's not finished yet but this
is gonna be really cool i'm thinking
what we do is we create like a chair and
tables down this is why like i made the
hole here
and i made it slightly longer at this
end so that maybe that there's a table
and chairs here so that we can sit and
have a meeting in here and it would just
be the most weird thing and then i'm
also planning on maybe having like
a little walkway so that you won't be
able to tell it's there unless you know
it's there so using this like the table
as the orientation point you can then
move around
and
use a little corridor to get out because
there is obviously needs to be a way out
but ah i love this
everyone wanted me to make this and i'm
glad i did i just didn't expect it to
take as long as it has
now i think we should crack on with this
getting this elevator done because mumbo
was nice enough to make a video for me
so
i might as well act on it
no not again this time i'm on the uh
this time on the outside
no
oh no i shouldn't have looked at him
is he gonna
no
[Music]
he can't go up
oh those screeches
so this is the first layer and i love
this it looks so good i haven't used it
yet which is kind of why you need an
elevator there's no way up here now we
just need to work our way up all the way
to the top and then we can start making
the different floors for this
i'm probably not going to put water in
this until the very that enderman is
still going
he's still he's still he's still mad at
me
and of course we're out
we're not quite in the next layer yet
now diving down there would be a very
silly mistake so we're gonna dive down
here and just glide in circles
let's see if we can get in oh
yep made it
layer one accomplished
can you get through one whole blocks
oh i did i'm getting really good at
flying you know
this looks like it might be the next
layer it is
so fortunately there's loads of space to
do the redstone that we need
each layer ah it's really impressive
inside each one of these i can't wait to
start filling this with stuff and here's
the chest full of all the bits and
pieces from red dog's tree
but this elevator has to go all the way
to the top so i hope that mumbo's design
works for really really tall elevators
and we made it to the top oh my goodness
and look at the mob party i really need
to get to work on turning this into a
mob farm because
that is just wasted potential
oh my goodness i need more hours in the
day so let's head over and take a look
at the elevator that mumbo has made for
me so here we are oh i immediately broke
it
this is why you don't press f5
oh no i've just i'm just breaking it
left right and center
oh no
i hope no redstone the buttons have gone
off
oh this is a nightmare
oh
if i put these back does it work
okay
uh i broke it but hopefully i fixed it
so this is the elevator that mumbo made
for me now this is genius i would have
never in a million years known
that if you send a redstone signal it
travels
upwards
through the glass it detects it or
something i don't really know how this
works does it detect a block down here
it must do so all of these are quite
simple each button
makes the redstone signal delay for
longer than the others they're all
linked up to one so all of them
technically go off but depending on
which button you click it delays it for
slightly longer
so i think that's how it works and then
once the signal hits this the timing is
just right so that the observer detects
it and then pushes you off
so hopefully this works
let's go to number two first
and
it
didn't push me out maybe it's slightly
off or maybe i maybe i broke it let's
try number one
i think the timing's slightly off maybe
i did break it because i definitely
tried this before and it worked and then
of course the one right at the top you
don't need to because he's actually oh
he's done a little tripwire hook here
that pushes it out so when you come out
the top
it just pushes you and then of course
you can go back down that's the other
thing this elevator works great because
at the bottom he's got a switcher he's
just improved it i was like theorizing
on how to do this but this is like a
really really sound design
but
i think i might actually need his help
genuinely to make this
so if we pretend that this is my base
this is where it is so i don't have the
luxury of being able to put the redstone
here as there is a wall directly there
so there there might need to be some
trickery going on there or moving around
this delay
so that it works but this is genuinely
really genius
really really genius
if it was timed correctly which i don't
think it is right now but
that is actually exactly what we need
thank you very much mumbo and uh this is
another request for uh please helping me
make it
so i'm afraid that's all i have time for
today i wasted so much time trying to
make those maps well succeeding to make
those maps let's not forget i might have
failed about a bajillion times but in
the end i actually made it it just cost
me hours and hours and hours
but it's a project well done and that
meeting room's gonna come in handy and i
think i've got some pretty genius ways
of keeping it secret
and
just the plans for this base are getting
bigger and bigger and bigger with every
episode we're gonna have a meeting room
we're gonna fill up these we're gonna
have an elevator that goes up and down
we're gonna add another layer up there
maybe even two layers a portal at the
top
these extend these tower extensions down
the end and we have the sand to do that
now it's so so exciting to build this
base i love it it may have started out
as this very small cylinder down here
but just look at what it has become and
also before i leave i just want to tell
you that in the tab you see my name i'm
the only one online which is a bit odd
but you see that there's my name and
then there's the number 10 now normally
that has the game time in or you know
block swam or something like that well
at the moment it counts how many
phantoms you have slain and there's like
a reward that if you slay the most
phantoms in the month that there's a
bunch of rewards that i think everyone's
sort of chipping into the reward pile
and i kind of want it but i don't know
if i can compete with the likes of
people that literally just stay up every
night in minecraft and just slay
phantoms but it might be something worth
doing especially as i'm not a rich man
i'm not a rich man here look i've got 23
diamond blocks some people have us you
know stacks in chests full of this stuff
anyway thank you very much for watching
i hope you did enjoy this video despite
it being full of many many fails this is
i think this is just like the beginning
this is beginning
and thank you very much again for
watching and good
bye